<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jieun Song  송지은</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jieun Song  송지은</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Speech perception in realistic environments</title>
      <link>/project/listening-effort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/listening-effort/</guid>
      <description>By examining neural responses to speech using Electroencephalography (EEG) across different stages of speech recognition, my research has investigated how listeners process speech in diverse adverse conditions (e.g., listening in a noisy environment, listening to second-language speech). People often report they have to “listen harder” in these difficult conditions, but it is not clear how this effort changes the processes involved in recognising speech. My research has demonstrated that greater listening effort exerted by non-native listeners as well as native listeners enhances their auditory processing, as measured by neural tracking of speech (see Song &amp;amp; Iverson, 2018; Song et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. L2 speech evaluation</title>
      <link>/project/automaticassessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/automaticassessment/</guid>
      <description>I worked with Prof. Ho-Young Lee at Seoul National University on a project evaluating English rhythm proficiency with measures of sentence stress. In a paper published in Applied Psycholinguistics in 2019, we showed that sentence stress scores of Korean learners of English were highly correlated with their overall speaking proficiency. This was part of a larger project with computer engineers where we built an automatic sentence stress feedback system for Korean learners of English, and this system was found to improve their pronunciation (published in Computer Speech and Language, 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Child Language Acquisition</title>
      <link>/project/language-acquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/language-acquisition/</guid>
      <description>I have been actively involved in other projects on child language development. I have written a book on child language acquisition with Dr. Jieun Kiaer at the University of Oxford, which was published in 2019 by a highly prestigious publishing house of South Korea, Science Books. While writing this monograph, I became more interested in broader issues on language development and multilingualism. I am collaborating with researchers at Seoul National University and Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Korean prosody</title>
      <link>/project/korean-prosody/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/korean-prosody/</guid>
      <description>I had great opportunities to take part in reseach projects on Korean intonation when I was a masters student at SNU. I am still continuing research in this area by working on a project on prosodic disambiguation of wh-words in Korean. This is collaborative work with Dr. Jieun Kiaer at the University of Oxford and Dr. Haesung Jeon at the University of Central Lancashire. In Korean, sentences with wh-words can</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>